時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
사쿠라지마에 들어간 무사시 일행은 시라누이 일족에게 최후의 결전을 도전하지만, 한조는 사츠마니아를 향해 미사일을 발사한다.
After getting into Sakurajima, Musashi and others challenge for the last decisive battle against Shiranui Clan,
but Hanzō launches a missile to Satsumania.
그러나 무사시의 활약으로 그걸 막았다.
But thanks to Musashi, it was stopped.
그렇지만 어머니의 면모를 보여준 히미코는 죽고 말았다.
But Himiko, who gave the feeling of mother, died.
코지로에게
이겼소!
I Defeated
Kojirō!
무사시? 어서 해.
Musashi? Finish it already!
조금만 있으면 끝나오!
I'm almost done-dasu!
무사시, 겉보기에 그 나무는 수령 300년은 넘은 것 같은데.
Musashi, that tree looks like it's more than 300 years old.
그런 나무에 오줌을 싸다니 뒤탈이 있을 게야.
You will be cursed, by peeing to a tree that old.
괜찮소! 아, 시원하오!
It'll be alright-dasu! I'm refreshed!
정말 왜 그러냐? 어디서든 오줌싸는 게 개같아!
What's wrong with you? You're peeing everywhere, like a dog!
센히메 님! 저는 그런 짓은 하지 않습니다.
Senhime! I do not do that.
정말, 코지로도 참. 멋진 척은. 나 알고 있소! 이 전에 노상방뇨한 걸.
Really, Kojirō, stop bragging off-dasu! I know that you peed outdoors before today-dasu.
-뭐, 뭐라고!?
-그만둬! 자, 오늘은 여기에 묵자.
-W- what did you say!?
-Forget it! Let's stay in here today.
또 나 오줌싸고 싶어졌소.
I want to pee again-dasu.
시원하오!
I'm refreshed-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
코지로! 오줌이오?
Kojirō! Are you here to pee-dasu?
무사시. 잘도 내가 노상방뇨한 걸 센히메 님 앞에서 밝혔겠다!
Musashi! How dare you reveal to Senhime that I peed outdoor!?
그렇지만 사실이오!
But that's true-dasu!
용서할 수 없다! 무사시, 승부다!
Unforgivable! Musashi, we'll have a match!
바라던 바오!
Just as I wanted-dasu!
간류 츠바메가에시!
Ganryu Tsubamegaeshi!
이천일류 섬광검!
Nitenichiryu: Flash Sword!
무사시, 끝장내라.
Musashi. Finish me.
세월의 정. 목숨만은 살려 주겠소.
Sympathy of years. I'll let you live-dasu.
코지로! 코지로! 코지로!
Kojirō! Kojirō! Kojirō!
죽으면 안 돼! 당신이 죽으면 저도 죽을 겁니다, 코지로!
Do not die! If you die, then I'll die too, Kojirō!
저, 오래 전부터 당신이 좋았어요. 그러니까, 그러니까 죽으면 안 돼요!
I loved you from a long time ago. So... please don't die!
센히메 님. 저도 마찬가지입니다. 공주님을 사랑하고 있었습니다.
Senhime, that's same for me. I love you, princess!
코지로! 둘이서 평범해도 좋으니가 행복하게 가정을 꾸려요!
Kojirō! Let's make make a happy household together, even if it's an ordinary one!
그럽시다. 아이는, 흠, 3명이 좋네요.
Let's do so. We'll have, um, 3 children!
여자아이라면, 나오코하고, 나오코하고, 나오코로 해요!
If they're girls, then let's name them Naoko, Naoko, and Naoko!
나오코가 한가득!
It's full of Naokos!
둘이서 서로 사랑하고 있었다니 전혀 몰랐소!
I didn't ever know that they loved each other-dasu!
그래도 어쨌든 이걸로 지팡구 제일이 되었소!
Anyway, I became the number one of Jipangu by this-dasu!
나 오츠루하고...
Otsuru and I will...
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
드디어 지팡구 제일이 되었구나! 오츠루 기뻐!
You finally become the number one of Jipangu! Otsuru's happy!
오츠루!
Otsuru!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
마치 꿈만 같소!
It's just like a dream-dasu!
아야야, 잘됐소, 꿈이 아니어서.
Ouch! What a relief-dasu! It's not a dream!
그래도 오츠루, 왜 여기에?
But, Otsuru, why are you here?
무사시 씨 만나고 싶어서, 만나고 싶어서 못 참았어!
I wanted to meet you, Mr. Musashi, so much and I couldn't hold it anymore!
무사시, 잘 됐구나. 분명 너라면 해낼 거라고 믿고 있었다.
Musashi, you did it! I always knew you would make it!
아, 타쿠안 스님까지 오셨소!
You're here too, Takuan-dasu!
기쁘지?
I hope you're happy!
조금만.
A little bit.
미야모토 마을의 사람들도 다 왔어!
Everyone from Miyamoto village is also here!
정말이오!?
Really-dasu!?
축! 무사시 지팡구 넘버원
Congratulations! Musashi is the Number One of Jipangu
에, 미야모토 마을의 무사시가 지팡구 제일이 된 걸 축하하는 의미로 건배!
Celebrating that Musashi from Miyamoto village became the number one of Jipangu, cheers!
건배!
Cheers!
귤 주스 맛있소!
Tangerine juice is delicious-dasu!
이야, 그래도 역시 무사시구나!
That's our Musashi!
정말, 얘 미야모토 마을의 자랑이야!
Really! That guy is the pride of Miyamoto village!
저건 정말 100년에 한번 나올까 말까 하는 천재 무예가야!
That guy really is the genius martial artist that rarely comes out once in 100 years!
정말이야, 정말.
True, true!
잠깐 안 본 새에 사내 다 되었구나.
You became a man while I wasn't seeing you!
이야, 부끄럽소!
You're making me shy-dasu!
어쨌든 사내다!
Anyway, you're the man!
강한데 뽐내지도 않고 말이야!
He's not bragging about his strength, too!
있잖아, 무사시 형, 지금까지 싸워온 이야기 해 줘!
Hey, Musashi bro, tell us about all the stories about your battles!
-그래, 그래!
-나도 듣고 싶다!
-Yeah, yeah!
-I want to hear, too!
그렇소?
Really-dasu?
그럼 내가 천공환하고 천지환을 손에 넣었을 때의 이야기를 하겠소.
Then let me tell my story about when I got Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru-dasu!
여행하고 있던 우리는 오니히메가 조종하는 츠치구모하고 싸우게 되었소.
During our journey, we had to fight Tsuchigumo controlled by Onihime-dasu.
あれは！
あれはまさしく天地丸！
だすけて。
おたまちゃん！
今行くだス！
なんだす！うわ！
土蜘蛛！
いきなり出るなんて秘境だす！
コジロー！
이 놈은 내게 맡겨라. 무사시는 저 아이를.
Leave this to me. Musashi, you rescue that girl.
さあ、来い、化け物！
오타마, 정신 차리시오!
Otama, get a grip!
さあ、おたまちゃん、おいらの背中に乗るだす。
ありがとう。
ムサシ！それはお玉ちゃんじゃない！
死ね、ムサシ！
아니, 뭔 짓이오!
What are you doing?!
死ね、ムサシ！
～するだス！
こんな年寄りをいじめる気か？
ばあちゃん。
ムサシ！
行け！土蜘蛛！
突きあり！
おせんちゃん！
助けて！
ベンケイ！
もう安心してくだされ！
저희도 괴물의 소문을 듣고 퇴치하러 왔습니다. 도와드리겠습니다!
We also heard about the monster and are here to exterminate! We'll help!
ウシワカ！
ほざくな！皆殺しにしてくれるわ！
뜨거!
Hot!
行け！土蜘蛛！
これは任せるだス！
ムサシ！気をつけろ！
あ？こたつが！
소중한 코테츠의 원한이오!
It's for the grudge of my precious Kotetsu-dasu!
츠치구모를 쓰러트리고 천지환을 손에 넣은 나는 다음에는 야마타노오로치하고 싸우게 되었소.
After taking Tsuchigumo down and obtaining Tenchimaru, I had to fight Yamata no Orochi.
이건 틀림없이 천공환!
This definitely is Tenkūmaru!
이렇게 나는 천공환, 천지환을 손에 넣었소.
And that's how I got Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru-dasu!
그럼 다음에는 홋카이도에서의 싸움 이야기를 하겠소.
Now, I'll tell about the battles I did in Hokkaido-dasu!
무사시 씨.
Mr. Musashi.
밖에서 계속 이야기해요.
Please keep talking outside.
자, 이 이상한 분위기는? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Now, what is this strange atmosphere? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
무사시 씨, 좀만 더 여기로 와.
Mr. Musashi, come here more.
알겠소.
Yes-dasu!
오츠루, 손 따뜻하오!
Otsuru, your hands are warm!
무사시 씨, 무사 수련의 여행은 힘들었지?
Mr. Musashi, the journey of training to become a swordman must've been difficult!
아니, 그 정도는 아니오. 내게는 큰 목표가 있으니 고되다고 생각은 했어도...
No, not that much-dasu. I have an objective, so even if it was tough...
그러고 보니 한번 나 사내의 울음을 보였던 적이 있소.
Thinking about that, I showed man's tears for once-dasu.
들려줘, 무사시.
Tell me, Mr. Musashi.
그 쯤, 우리는 규슈에서 시라누이 일족하고 싸우고 있었소.
At that time, we were fighting against Shiranui Clan-dasu.
このよに～かぎり、退治するのがおいらの役目い！
二天一流の剣の差異を見せてやるだす！
～かぶとわり！
아파아파!
It hurts, it hurts!
엄마! 아파아파!
Mommy! It hurts, it hurts!
엄마! 아파!
Mommy! It hurts!
왜 그러니, 무사시?
What's wrong, Musashi?
おいら、転んじゃったもん。
あら、痛かったわね。痛いの痛いの飛んで行け！
ほら！もう大丈夫でしょう？
もう痛くない。
母ちゃん。
母ちゃん！
夢か。。。
ムサシさん、気が付きましたね。
母ちゃん。。。
嫌ですわ、ムサシさん。
本当にこうしてると、おいら、母ちゃんといるみたいだス。
私はそんなにムサシさんのお母様に似ているかしら。
いや、おいら、母ちゃんにあったことないだスけど、
気が付いたら独りぼっちだっただスから。
そうなの。
もしいたら、きっとヒミコさんのようじゃないかって。
いい気分だすな、ウンゼンまできた～あったってもんだす！
히미코 씨는 정말 상냥하고 정말 엄마 같았소.
Ms. Himiko was really kind, and she was as if my mother-dasu.
그래도...
But...
무사시! 저 히미코라는 여자는 시라누이 일족의 여왕이야!
Musashi! That Himiko woman is the queen of Shiranui Clan!
そんなことあるわけないんだす！
내가 확인했어! 틀림없어!
I checked it and there's no doubt about it!
ヒミコさんは、おいらに優しくしてくれたんだす！その人は！
저 여자는 우리 적이야!
That woman is our enemy!
いうな！聞きたく無いだス！
聞きたくないだす。
わかったよ、ムサシ。
나, 그 상냥한 히미코 씨가 시라누이의 여왕이라니 믿을 수 없었소. 그래서 시라누이의 본거지, 사쿠라지마에 들어가서...
I couldn't believe that kind Ms. Himiko was a queen of Shiranui-dasu.
That's why I went to Sakurajima, the base of Shiranui...
제군! 때가 왔다!
Everyone! The time has come!
제너럴 이에야스를 쓰러트리고 지팡구국을 우리 수중에 넣을 것이다!
We will take General Ieyasu down and claim Jipangu State into our hands!
지라이얀이 말한 대로 히미코 씨는 시라누이의 여왕이었소...
Just like Jiraiyan said, Ms. Himiko is the queen of Shiranui...
히미코 님! 히미코 님!
Lord Himiko! Lord Himiko!
皆のもの。聞いてくれ。我らの～ため、あらたな仲間が力を貸してくれることになった。
さ、ハンゾウ殿。
諸君！我々の目的達成のためには、まず不知火一族が～、ジパング国を転覆させることにある。
皆のもの！我らとハンゾウに勝利の誓いを！
おう！ヒミコ女王様！おう！ハンゾウ殿！
そこのもの、どこへ行く！
어, 그게, 저, 왠지 흥분해서 소변을 보고 싶어졌소.
Um, err, that's, I was so excited that I want to urinate-dasu.
だす。
いやいや、行くでゴワス。
顔を見せてみろ。
い、いや、お見せするほどの顔じゃないだす。
じゃなくて、ゴワス。
ああ、やめるでゴワス！
무사시? 무사시, 너!
Musashi?! Musashi, you!
히미코 씨! 아니, 히미코!
Ms. Himiko! No, Himiko!
よくも俺を騙してくれたんだすな！
騙されるほうがバカなのさ。
그래도 여전히 그 멍청함은 안 고쳐졌나 보구나.
But as usual, your idiocy wasn't fixed after all!
のこのこと不知火の本拠地に乗り込んでくるとはな。
その～おいらのいいところだす！
ほざくな、小僧！
くそ！
こんどこそあの世に送り返してやる！
なに？！
ジライヤン！
ムサシ！
ジライヤン、すまんだす。やっぱりヒミコは不知火一族の女王だっただス。
もういいから、とにかく逃げるんだ！
그래서? 어쨌어?
And? What happened?
한조가 히미코 씨를 배신해서 히미코 씨가 죽었소.
Hanzō betrayed Ms. Himiko and Ms. Himiko died-dasu.
ムサシ。私を許してくれますか？
む、ムサシ。最後にお母さんと呼んでくれ。
母ちゃん！
정말 쓰라렸겠구나.
That must've been hurt.
그렇소.
Right-dasu.
어, 오츠루, 언제 꼬리가 달렸소?
Er, Otsuru, when did you get a tail-dasu?
어? 어! 만두가 하늘을 난다!
Huh? Wha-!? A dumpling is flying!
어, 어디에 날고 있소?
Huh? W- where is it flying-dasu?
안 보이오!
I can't see it-dasu!
어라?
Huh?
나, 잠에 취했소.
Maybe I'm half asleep-dasu.
여기! 무사시 씨가 좋아하는 주먹밥!
Here! Your favorite rice balls!
와, 나 오츠루의 주먹밥이 제일 좋소!
Otsuru's rice balls are the best-dasu!
따, 딱딱하오.
T- they're hard-dasu.
무사시 놈, 저런 낡아빠진 집 위에 올라서 뭘 하는 거야?
What is that Musashi doing on a worn-out house?
잠 덜 깼나...
I wonder if he's half asleep.
저, 저거 봐봐!
L- look at that!
센히메 님이 있네요.
Senhime, you're there.
코지로도.
You too, Kojirō.
저런저런, 또 너구리에게 속았군요.
Oh my, he's fooled by raccoons again.
아, 여관 주인분이시군요.
Oh, you must be the owner of this inn.
너구리한테 속다니 무슨 소리에요?
What do you mean by being fooled by raccoons?
저 무예가, 저기 큰 나무에 오줌을 쌌지?
Didn't that martial artist peed on that big tree?
네, 어제 조금...
Yes, he did that yesterday...
(타누키: 너구리, 키: 나무)
(tanuki: raccoon, ki: tree)
그러니까 그렇지. 저 나무는 너구리나무. 이 주변 너구리의 수호신이야.
I knew it. That tree is called Raccoon Tree. It's the guardian god of raccoon around this place.
근데 거기에 오줌을 쌌으니 너구리들이 화났겠지.
But since he peed on there, raccoons got angry!
따, 딱딱하오.
T- they're hard-dasu!
너구리한테 속다니 한심한 놈! 완전 무예가로 생각할 수가 없군!
How can he be fooled by raccoons?! How miserable! He's a pathetic excuse for a martial artist!
-정말이야.
-일류 무예가라면 너구리하고 인간의 구별 정도는 갈 터!
Agreed.
First class martial artists should be able to distinguish between raccoons and humans!
아, 그래그래, 숙박비가 아직이군요.
Oh, right. You have to pay for the stay.
아, 실례했습니다. 300문이었지요?
Oh, excuse me. It was 300 mons, right?
감사합니다.
Thank you so much.
바보 자식!
You fool!
너, 너구리.
R- raccoon!
일류 무예가라면 너구리하고 인간의 구별이 가는 거 아니었어?!
Can't first class martial artists distinguish between raccoons and humans?!
오츠루, 이 주먹밥 딱딱하오.
Otsuru, this rice ball is hard-dasu!
지팡구 제일이 되었다 생각했더니 너구리한테 속았다니, 정말이지 무사시답구나.
When he thought he became the number one of Jipangu, he was simply fooled by raccoons. That's totally Musashi.
그러나 기죽지 마라, 무사시! 밝은 내일이 기다린다!
But don't be discouraged, Musashi! A bright tomorrow is waiting for you!
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
자, 돌아왔소, 에도토피아!
We're finally back at Edotopia-dasu!
거기에는 이번에야말로 진짜 오츠루가 있소!
The real Otsuru is there this time-dasu!
나, 기쁘오!
I'm happy-dasu!
기다리고 기다렸던 무예 대회도 시작되니, 나, 제일이 되기 위해서 힘내오!
The marial artist competition that I've been waiting for is about to begin, so I'm going to do my best-dasu!
그런데 그 쯤, 한조가 수수께끼의 집단에 들어가오!
But meanwhile, Hanzō joins a mysterious group!
다음 이야기! 나왔다 수수께끼의 육도마왕이오
Next story! He Appeared! Mysterious Rikudomaoh
질풍노도의 미야코 팔레스이오!
It's the stormy Miyako Palace-dasu!
다음 이야기
나왔다 수수께끼의
육도마왕이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
He Appeared!
Mysterious Rikudomaoh
Look forwards for it!